http://linkedin.com/in/husna-bakhshi-baa939186

Cover Letter

September 12, 2022

Dear Hiring Manager,

I am presenting myself as potential candidate for this position at your Scotiabank. I believe I am an excellent candidate for this position due to my background knowledge, experience, and huge interest in field of software and technology. I have obtained significant skills during my Field Epidemiology Training Program (FETP) Fellowship including working on different software while doing health related research.

Moreover, currently, I am enrolled in Health Informatics Technology Program in Centennial College to gain more in-depth knowledge in innovative technology of data analysis, visualization, and data management. I am involved working in college projects like Java, python, HTML, CSS, SQL, Git/GitHub. I want to expand my knowledge more in this field. I would glad to have this huge opportunity in Scotiabank. My 2+ years of related experience in designing websites for business is another added value that make a potential candidate for position.

As a National Surveillance Officer and FETP fellow in my past work at Ministry of Health, I have developed skills in software, data analysis, database development and teamwork.

I would love to be part of the team due to their contribution in advancement of new technology and information. Given my interest and background in information technology, it would an extraordinary opportunity to contribute to innovative projects.

I look forward to the opportunity to attend an interview and discuss more about my qualifications for this position in detail. Thank you in advance for your time and consideration of my application. In case of more queries about my qualifications, you may kindly reach me at husna.bakhshi@yahoo.com mobile #: 437-219-9126.

Sincerely, Husna Bakhshi

Resume

Detail-oriented | Data Analysis | Teamwork

- Current student of Health Informatics Technology with highest grades
- Recent graduate of Field Epidemiology Training Program (FETP) Fellowship
- 4+ years of experience in scientific research and data management
- Trained on statistical tools, such as Stata, SPSS, Epi Info, CS pro, etc.
- Skilled at literature reviews, proposal writing, database development, and data analysis
- Strong communication skills; multilingual in English, Dari, Pashtu and Urdu
- Computer skills include proficiency in Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint

Education

Health Informatics Technology Diploma

September 2021 - Current

Centennial College, Toronto, ON/Canada

Relevant topics: programming (C#); Database Development (Java, HTML); Software Requirements

Field Epidemiology Training Program (FETP) Fellowship

August 2015 - December 2017

CDC USA, Dushanbe, Tajikistan

- Relevant Courses: Outbreak Investigation; Surveillance; Data Analysis (Epi-info, SPSS, Stata, CS Pro)
- *Projects:* Completed papers on outbreak investigation; funded a research project on a Road Traffic Injury Surveillance system in Kabul, Afghanistan

Bachelor of Science in Public Health (BSPH)

April 2011 - December 2014

Kabul Medical University, Kabul/Afghanistan

- Relevant Courses: Epidemiology (descriptive and analytical studies); Biostatistics; Principles of Public
 Health; Behavioral Science; Health Promotion; Lifestyle and Health; Health System; Environmental Health;
 Health Policy & Economy; Sexual and Reproductive Health; Occupational Health; Global Health; Mental
 Health; Drug and Substance Abuse
- Project: Thesis on Energy Beverages and Its Effects on Health

Work Experience

Retail Associate Cashier

February 2019- March 2020

Compass Group Canada

Oshawa, ON/ Canada

- Excellent communication with customers on daily bases to meet their needs
- Developed and maintained system for stock and inventory management
- Prepare invoices for customer purchase

Tele-research Volunteer at Post- Polio Registry Initiative

January 2019- October 2019

March of Dimes

Toronto, ON/ Canada

- Conducted follow-up investigation of more than 100 post-polio survivors through phone calls
- Entered the data in the organization database
- Reviewed the accuracy of data for quality insurance
- Delivered accurate and timely research support to ensure the information of post-polio survivors are updated
- Provided outreach to Stroke Survivors who are referred from local hospitals by providing them with the resources available to help them re-engage into community.

National Surveillance Officer

Ministry of Public Health

January 2016- August 2018 Kabul/ Afghanistan

- Conducted outbreak investigation of priority disease in Afghanistan
- Traced contacts of epidemic-prone diseases in the country
- Reviewed the line list and surveillance data in the national surveillance database to ensure the accuracy, timeliness, completeness and overall quality of data
- Analyzed the national data for determining the outbreak threshold for epidemic-prone diseases
- Developed weekly & monthly epidemiology report for policy & program decisions
- Developed research study protocols and reports based on national surveillance data
- Worked on scientific research studies papers for guiding health system policies & plan
- Provided administrative & operational support for outbreak incident command system

Research Intern in Health Economy & Finance

Ministry of Public Health

July 2015- August 2015 Kabul/ Afghanistan

- Conducted literature review on hospital & health system finance
- Conducted desk-review of policy documents on National Health Account, Public Expenditure Tracking System, Result Based Financing, Social Health Insurance, Expenditure Management Information System, Revenue Generation for Health Sector
- Entered the hospital expenses data in the system database
- Communicated with hospitals for timely entry and completion of hospital expenses data
- Supported in analyzing the hospital expenditure data
- Supported in developed national health account survey report

Health Coordinator for Sero- Survey, CDC Atlanta Funded ProjectMinistry of Public Health

April 2015- July 2015 Kabul/ Afghanistan

- Coordinated with hospital to identify target patients
- Collected data and specimens from patients
- Managed the data with the analysis team
- Provided weekly reports to the ministry and country project lead

Research Experience

- Piloting of a Road Traffic Injury Surveillance System in the Emergency Units of Two Traumatic Public Hospitals, Kabul City, Afghanistan, Sep/2018, Principal Investigator.
- Determinants of Institutional Delivery Among Ever Married Women in Afghanistan- Evidence from the Demographic Health Survey (AfDHS, 2015), Jan/2018, Co- investigator.
- National Influenza Surveillance Assessment in 9 Regional Provinces of Afghanistan, Dec/2016, Principal Investigator.
- Prevalence of Drug use and Related Factors among Kabul Medical University Students, Dec/2014, Principal Investigator.
- Thesis on Energy Beverages and Its Effects on Health, Literature Review, Dec/2014, Principal Investigator.

Achievements

- Selected as a presenter for 3 outbreak investigation abstracts in the 10th International Conference on Emerging Infections Diseases, Atlanta, USA - Aug. 2018
- Selected among top 3 excellent students to attend Epidemic Intelligence Service (EIS) conference, Atlanta, USA – 2017 and 2018
- Selected in the FETP program among 100+ participants from all around the country